<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Redshift]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Redshift</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:14:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:14:00 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[The black-box method]]></title><description><![CDATA[Source: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RDzsrmMl48I" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RDzsrmMl48I" target="_self">Colen Galen - The Black-Box method: how to learn anything quickly</a>A Black box can be thought of as a function that does something, we know what it does, but we don't know how it does it. Sort of like neural networks. Why is this useful? Whenever you want to learn or make something, it's concepts take time to learn. The harder the concept is, the more time it will take.<br>
<img alt="ThingsTakeTime.gif" src="files/thingstaketime.gif" target="_self">But you only have limited time! - So, to understand things faster, we can black-box them, only learning the what and not the how.<br>
<img alt="Blackboxd.gif" src="files/blackboxd.gif" target="_self">Blackbox isn't a substitute for learning. It's a way to map out what you need to know faster. When you later need to make an edit to how the thing works, you will have to learn the underlying concept.
Works quickly - This will make things that may take hours or days to understand into things that will take mere minutes.
Let's you know where to look - It lets you have most of the necessary information later. It will know where to look for in your project.
Let's you identify related problems - Knowing the blackbox, it will help you identify when a problem uses a certain concept.
]]></description><link>the-black-box-method.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Art Of Learning/The black-box method.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:39:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="files/thingstaketime.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;files/thingstaketime.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>