<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Redshift]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Redshift</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:29:55 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[There's not really that much to learn! What if you're just stupid.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Recently, I've been needing to learn a whole ton of stuff. Related to CS, Physics and especially have had to pick up on a WHOLE LOT of math. I thought it'd require hours upon hours of practice - but what I found was... There's not really a whole lot to learn! Actually, it's kind of disappointing how little there is!The main reason why learning new concepts feels like a drag to most people, seems to be long, arduous, and irrelevant lectures and weird fancy tricks they're trying to use to learn. When in reality, you can just gobble down information from textbooks as long as you have the pre-requisites!Really, stop trying to look around for 'hacks' or weird 'alternate learning methods' to learn things, textbooks are good. You need to be able to read heavily detalied textbooks. Pre-requisites i.e. established concepts on top of which the newer concepts are built, are obviously important. Learning is like building a massive stack of cards, if you don't have the cards at the bottom, how are you going to place the cards above? It's not that the cards will be shaky, they literally, physically, can't be placed! Think of it like, levelling up in an RPG (though I don't like that overused analogy much, but it does get the job done.) Every-time you level up, it becomes easier to do certain tasks, and also you unlock new things/upgrades you can use. You can think of it like the research tree in Factorio even, you can't really research new tools, without already having researched the things beforehand. That's exactly the point here.Of course, researching every-single thing may be time-consuming, and even if still possible (And it very much is!) may not be practical - say you need to learn something on the spot for a hackathon or something, of course, you won't go about learning every single concept there in detail! You'll just look at "what goes in" and "what comes out" for now, and you can fill those things in later to optimise your knowledge. :) I have another blog on this exact concept <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The black-box method" data-href="The black-box method" href="the-art-of-learning/the-black-box-method.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">here.</a>GOBBLE GOBBLE GOBBLE]]></description><link>there&apos;s-not-really-that-much-to-learn!-what-if-you&apos;re-just-stupid..html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Art Of Learning/There&apos;s not really that much to learn! What if you&apos;re just stupid..md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:23:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>